Let's start by cleaning up our main dot art file.
We can rename our up to flutter social UI
and then we'll change the theme data to primary color colors upload
and then below our my app class.
We can delete the my homepage.
Class and then for the home we'll type in like screen.
Now let's create a screen folder inside of lib directory.
We're going to make a file called like an underscore screen that.
And this is going to be a straightforward.
And I can type in SDF which is the shortcut using the V S code extension.
Awesome folder snippets.
Hit enter and then log in screen remember to import material by hovering over safe widget holding down
command period on Mac and then selecting material daughter after that.
Let's have our log in screen return a scaffold
and it's safe.
Now go back to main that are and then we can import the log and screen and then to remove the debug
banner in the top right.
Right under title we can add debug show checked mode banner and set out to false.
Let's take a look at our log in screen UI we can see that we have an image here with a custom clipper.
We have a text widget and then two text fields and below that we have a flat button and then a container
at the bottom of the screen giving us an option to sign up.
Now let's go to our logon screen daughter and we start building out the screen for the screen.
We're going to be using a single child scroll view
and you may be thinking that we could also use a list to you.
But the problem with the list view is that we're not able to have our image go underneath our style
bar if we have a lost view than the image is going to start over here.
But by using a single child scroll view the image will be able to go underneath the status bar.
We're going to make a container with it.
And we need to specify the height of the container.
And that's just going to be media query out of context that size dot height
and that's our scroll view takes up our entire screen.
Now this container will contain a column widget and inside a column widget we're going to have each
of the different widgets so let's create a child.
Column children our first child will be an image so so image image asset image and then we're going
to pass in the location of our image in our file tree.
And that's going to be an asset.
Images log in to underscore background deejay Peg
that's it save and we see that the image appeared up here next at the height of the image we'll set
it to media query out of context dot size dot height divided by 2.5
and then in order to make it feel up to the top of the screen we need to add a fit on this box fit dot
cover
and in order to make sure our image always takes up the entire width of our container we can also add
the width property and you stumbled on Infinity next let's add the texture underneath image we'll create
a text widget and it'll say frenzy
what a style to
textile color themed out of context our primary color and that's the blue color we set in our made out
our file here
font size 30 4.0 font weight font weight doubled we'll see what the letter spacing to 1.0 it's save
and now we have our text appearing here.
Now let's work on adding these two text fields each with a prefix icon we're going to first add a size
box of height ten point 0.
After that we're going to create our text field and our textual who's going to have a decoration input
decoration
and if we add save we can see our textual appears inside the input recreation we're going to have the
property for color colors that way.
And that's the color of the inside of a text field in order to see the full color.
We need to set filled to true.
And then will the text to username.
Now it's at the prefix icon icon icons that account box
and set these sides to thirty point 0
looking at our.
You are here we can see that the user name label is not in line with the icon and the way we fix that
is by adding content padding to our input decoration and selling that to edge inserts.
That's a metric vertical fifteen point 0 and it save it up bumped our techs down a little bit.
Lastly a thousand padding to our text field
edge inserts dot symmetric horizontal twenty point 0 vertical ten point 0
and now we have our first X field
now for our second text field let's copy this here including the size box and the padding tax yield
it save and we have our next X field we can remove user name and replace it with password
and then I can start a count box we can start as icons dot LOC
and since this is a password field we want to be able to obscure the text because we don't want users
to see the password so inside text field but outside decoration will set obscure text to true and it
save now we can't see what we're typing for the button underneath our two text fields we're going to
create a container
we'll solve the margins to edge insert that symmetric horizontal sixty point of
the decoration box decoration color deemed out of context the primary color and also include the border
radius border radius dots circular thirty point 0 and remember to add a height so we can see the container
what are the child text.
Text in and our container shrunk to the size of our text.
So what are the align property to our container alignment.
Center and now our container expanded and we can style our text by doing textile color colors not white
font size twenty two point two font weight font weight that w 600 letter spacing.
Also to one point five and it save and it looks like I put too much border on our button so let's reduce
it to four radius at Circular ten point 0 and then we can add a size box read about our container height
forty point A
in order to make the container clickable we're going to wrap our container in a gesture detector
and add on top
for the final widget of our logon screen we need to add the container down here and when we do that
is by going underneath our duster detector and we'll make the container the alignment will be alignment
that center just like we did with our previous container of the color theme Don of context dot primary
color
the height also to eighty point so noted safe and we see that our container appears right here let's
add the child tax before we push it down to the bottom so say don't have an account
and remember to add the apostrophe here so we escape it with the backslash sign up
and for styling textile
color colors that way font size twenty point font wait aren't we.
The W 500.
Now let's wrap our container in a gesture detector to make it clickable gesture detector on top giving
an empty method and to push our container down to the bottom of the screen we need to wrap our gesture
detector with a new widget called a line alignment fractional offset dot bottom center and that's going
to align our container to the bottom center of the bounce around it and then we wrap our line with it
then expanded and once we save we're going to see the container be pushed all the way down to the bottom
the expanded widget is allowing the container to take up the rest of the screen and then align the container
to the bottom center sticks it to the bottom.
So now for the keyboard comes up
we see that the container has still stuck on the bottom.